<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>resticprofile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/index.html</link><description>Configuration profiles manager for restic backup</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:22:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/index.html</guid><description>Pre-built binaries Linux mac OS Windows Ansible Source Upgrade Docker Shell Completion</description></item><item><title>Configuration file</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/configuration/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/configuration/index.html</guid><description>A configuration is a set of profiles. Each profile is in a new section that has the name of the profile. Inside each profile, you can specify different flags for each command. A command definition is in a subsection of the name of the command. ​ toml yaml hcl json [profile_name] [profile_name.backup] profile_name: backup: profile_name { backup = { } } { "profile_name": { "backup": { } } } All the restic flags can be defined in a section. For most of them you just need to remove the two dashes in front.</description></item><item><title>Using resticprofile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/usage/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/usage/index.html</guid><description>Here are a few examples how to run resticprofile (using the main example configuration file)
See all snapshots of your default profile:
resticprofile See all available profiles in your configuration file (and the restic commands where some flags are defined):
resticprofile profiles Profiles available (name, sections, description): root: (backup, copy, forget, retention) self: (backup, check, copy, forget, retention) src: (backup, copy, retention, snapshots) Groups available (name, profiles, description): full-backup: [root, src] Backup root &amp; src profiles (using full-backup group shown earlier)</description></item><item><title>Schedules</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/schedules/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/schedules/index.html</guid><description>Scheduler resticprofile manages scheduled backups using:
launchd on macOS Task Scheduler on Windows systemd on Linux and other BSDs crond as a fallback (requires crontab binary) crontab files (with or without a user column) On Unix systems (excluding macOS), resticprofile uses systemd if available, otherwise it falls back to crond.
See reference / global section for scheduler configuration options.
Each profile can be scheduled independently. Within each profile, these sections can be scheduled:</description></item><item><title>Monitoring</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/monitoring/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/monitoring/index.html</guid><description>Status file Prometheus</description></item><item><title>Resticprofile configuration reference</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:22:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/index.html</guid><description>Note The configuration file reference is generated from resticprofile’s data model and restic’s manual pages.
Section global Section Profile backup cache cat check copy diff dump features find forget init key key-add key-list key-passwd key-remove list ls migrate mount options prune rebuild-index recover repair repair-index repair-packs repair-snapshots restore retention rewrite snapshots stats tag unlock Nested Sections ScheduleBaseConfig ScheduleConfig SendMonitoringHeader SendMonitoringSection StreamErrorSection Section Groups Value types JSON Schema</description></item><item><title>Contributions</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/contributions/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/contributions/index.html</guid><description>Please share your resticprofile recipes, fancy configuration files, or tips and tricks.
I have created a contributions section for that matter.
shell completion export status to grafana send email on systemd timer error get backup status information in zabbix scheduling inside a docker container backup stats in InfluxDB via Telegraf use a protected folder for configuration on Windows</description></item><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/changelog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/changelog/index.html</guid><description>v0.31.0 (2025-05-26) 🍸 Spring Bank Holiday release 🌞 This release includes several long-awaited improvements.
Improvements: Add support for the new Restic flag exclude-cloud-files introduced in version 0.18.0 (Windows only). Include missing run-* and send-* targets in all commands (previously missing in check and copy commands). Send Restic version as a new Prometheus metric. Support .yml files when searching for configuration files (previously only .yaml was considered). Bug fixes: Ignore missing drop-in files to prevent creating an empty systemd schedule. Changelog Add missing run-* and send-* to all command sections (#504) add support for windows only flag exclude-cloud-files (#500) add support for yml extension when searching for configuration file (#506) add version of restic to the Prometheus metrics (#495) fix: remove duplicated field ignore missing drop-in files to avoid creating an empty configuration (#502) replace deprecated sonar scan action (#503) v0.30.1 (2025-05-05) 🐛 Bug fix release 🐞 This releases fixes a regression bug when scheduling system tasks with systemd: in some cases the HOME directory was replaced by the home directory of the user who ran the sudo command</description></item></channel></rss>