<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nested Sections :: resticprofile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/index.html</link><description>Nested profile sections Nested sections describe configuration structure that is assigned to flags within the configuration, see HTTP Hooks as an example.
ScheduleBaseConfig ScheduleConfig SendMonitoringHeader SendMonitoringSection StreamErrorSection</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ScheduleBaseConfig</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/schedulebaseconfig/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/schedulebaseconfig/index.html</guid><description>Nested ScheduleBaseConfig Name Type Default Notes after-network-online true / false Don’t start this schedule when the network is offline (supported in “systemd”) capture-environment one or more strings RESTIC_* Set names (or glob expressions) of environment variables to capture during schedule creation. The captured environment is applied prior to “profile.env” when running the schedule. Whether capturing is supported depends on the type of scheduler being used (supported in “systemd” and “launchd”) command-output string auto Sets the destination for command output (stderr/stdout). “log” sends output to the log file (if specified), “console” sends it to the console instead. “auto” sends it to “both” if console is a terminal otherwise to “log” only - see configuration/logs/. Is one of auto, log, console, all ignore-on-battery true / false false Don’t start this schedule when running on battery ignore-on-battery-less-than integer Don’t start this schedule when running on battery and the state of charge is less than this percentage. Examples: 20, 33, 50, 75 lock-mode string default Specify how locks are used when running on schedule - see schedules/configuration/. Is one of default, fail, ignore lock-wait integer OR duration Set the maximum time to wait for acquiring locks when running on schedule. Examples: 150s, 15m, 30m, 45m, 1h, 2h30m log string Redirect the output into a log file or to syslog when running on schedule - see configuration/logs/. Examples: /resticprofile.log, syslog-tcp://syslog-server:514, syslog:server, syslog: permission string auto Specify whether the schedule runs with system or user privileges - see schedules/configuration/. Is one of auto, system, user, user_logged_on priority string standard Set the priority at which the schedule is run. Is one of background, standard systemd-drop-in-files one or more strings Files containing systemd drop-in (override) files - see schedules/systemd/</description></item><item><title>ScheduleConfig</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/scheduleconfig/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/scheduleconfig/index.html</guid><description>Nested ScheduleConfig Schedule configuration structure. Can be used to define schedules in profiles and groups.
Name Type Default Notes after-network-online true / false Don’t start this schedule when the network is offline (supported in “systemd”) at one or more strings Set the times at which the scheduled command is run (times are specified in systemd timer format). Examples: hourly, daily, weekly, monthly, 10:00,14:00,18:00,22:00, Wed,Fri 17:48, *-*-15 02:45, Mon..Fri 00:30 capture-environment one or more strings RESTIC_* Set names (or glob expressions) of environment variables to capture during schedule creation. The captured environment is applied prior to “profile.env” when running the schedule. Whether capturing is supported depends on the type of scheduler being used (supported in “systemd” and “launchd”) command-output string auto Sets the destination for command output (stderr/stdout). “log” sends output to the log file (if specified), “console” sends it to the console instead. “auto” sends it to “both” if console is a terminal otherwise to “log” only - see configuration/logs/. Is one of auto, log, console, all ignore-on-battery true / false false Don’t start this schedule when running on battery ignore-on-battery-less-than integer Don’t start this schedule when running on battery and the state of charge is less than this percentage. Examples: 20, 33, 50, 75 lock-mode string default Specify how locks are used when running on schedule - see schedules/configuration/. Is one of default, fail, ignore lock-wait integer OR duration Set the maximum time to wait for acquiring locks when running on schedule. Examples: 150s, 15m, 30m, 45m, 1h, 2h30m log string Redirect the output into a log file or to syslog when running on schedule - see configuration/logs/. Examples: /resticprofile.log, syslog-tcp://syslog-server:514, syslog:server, syslog: permission string auto Specify whether the schedule runs with system or user privileges - see schedules/configuration/. Is one of auto, system, user, user_logged_on priority string standard Set the priority at which the schedule is run. Is one of background, standard systemd-drop-in-files one or more strings Files containing systemd drop-in (override) files - see schedules/systemd/</description></item><item><title>SendMonitoringHeader</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/sendmonitoringheader/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/sendmonitoringheader/index.html</guid><description>Nested SendMonitoringHeader Name Type Default Notes name string Name of the HTTP header. Examples: "Authorization", "Cache-Control", "Content-Disposition", "Content-Type" value string Value of the header. Examples: "Bearer ...", "Basic ...", "no-cache", "attachment; filename=stats.txt", "application/json", "text/plain", "text/xml"</description></item><item><title>SendMonitoringSection</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/sendmonitoringsection/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/sendmonitoringsection/index.html</guid><description>Nested SendMonitoringSection Name Type Default Notes body string Request body, overrides “body-template” body-template string Path to a file containing the request body (go template). See configuration/http_hooks/#body-template headers one or more nested SendMonitoringHeader Additional HTTP headers to send with the request method string GET HTTP method of the request. Is one of GET, DELETE, HEAD, OPTIONS, PATCH, POST, PUT, TRACE skip-tls-verification true / false false Enables insecure TLS (without verification), see also “global.ca-certificates” url uri URL of the target to send to</description></item><item><title>StreamErrorSection</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/streamerrorsection/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/streamerrorsection/index.html</guid><description>Nested StreamErrorSection Name Type Default Notes max-runs integer 0 Maximum amount of times that “run” is started ; 0 for no limit. Must be >= 0 min-matches integer 0 Minimum amount of times the “pattern” must match before “run” is started ; 0 for no limit. Must be >= 0 pattern regex A regular expression pattern that is tested against stderr of a running restic command run string The shell command to run when the pattern matches</description></item></channel></rss>