<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resticprofile configuration reference :: resticprofile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/index.html</link><description> Note The configuration file reference is generated from resticprofile’s data model and restic’s manual pages.
Section global Section Profile backup cache cat check copy diff dump find forget init key key-add key-list key-passwd key-remove list ls migrate mount prune rebuild-index recover repair repair-index repair-packs repair-snapshots restore retention rewrite snapshots stats tag unlock Nested Sections ScheduleBaseConfig ScheduleConfig SendMonitoringHeader SendMonitoringSection StreamErrorSection Section Groups Value types JSON Schema</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Section global</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/global/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/global/index.html</guid><description>Section global The global section is at the root of the configuration file and contains the global settings for resticprofile.
Name Type Default Notes ca-certificates one or more strings Path to PEM encoded certificates to trust in addition to system certificates when resticprofile sends to a webhook - see configuration/http_hooks/ command-output string auto Sets the destination for command output (stderr/stdout). “log” sends output to the log file (if specified), “console” sends it to the console instead.</description></item><item><title>Section Profile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/profile/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/profile/index.html</guid><description>Profile sections In config file format v1, the name of this section is the name of your profile (excluding reserved names like global, groups, includes &amp; version).
From config file format v2, profile sections are declared as named configuration structure below section profiles (see Configuration v2 for details).
Section profile Flags used by resticprofile only: Name Type Default Notes base-dir string Sets the working directory for this profile. The profile will fail when the working directory cannot be changed.</description></item><item><title>Nested Sections</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/nested/index.html</guid><description>Nested profile sections Nested sections describe configuration structure that is assigned to flags within the configuration, see HTTP Hooks as an example.
ScheduleBaseConfig ScheduleConfig SendMonitoringHeader SendMonitoringSection StreamErrorSection</description></item><item><title>Section Groups</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/groups/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/groups/index.html</guid><description>Section groups Config file format v1 uses a simplified groups section. Every named item below groups maps to one or more profile names (list of strings).
From file format v2, every named item in the groups section is configuration structure following the format described below (see Configuration v2 for details):
Name Type Default Notes continue-on-error true / false auto Continue with the next profile on a failure, overrides “global.group-continue-on-error” description string Describe the group profiles one or more strings Names of the profiles belonging to this group schedules key => nested ScheduleConfig Allows to run the group on schedule for the specified command name</description></item><item><title>Value types</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/value-types/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/value-types/index.html</guid><description>Type: true / false Is a boolean value to toggle a flag or specific behaviour that has to match the syntax for booleans in the used file format. Type: numeric &amp; integer Is a numeric value (whole-number for integer) that has to match the syntax for numbers in the used file format. Type: string Is a sequence of UTF-8 characters that usually have to be placed in quotes and must match the syntax for strings in the used file format.</description></item><item><title>JSON Schema</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/json-schema/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/reference/json-schema/index.html</guid><description>resticprofile provides a JSON schema for v1 &amp; v2 configuration files. The schema may be used to validate configuration files in JSON format (and possibly others), see JSON schema for details.
JSON schema URLs for any restic version:
Config V1: https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1.json Config V2: https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2.json JSON schema URLs for a specific restic version:
.../config-1-restic-{MAJOR}-{MINOR}.json .../config-2-restic-{MAJOR}-{MINOR}.json Available URLs:
https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-17.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-17.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-16.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-15.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-15.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-14.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-14.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-2-restic-0-13.json https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/jsonschema/config-1-restic-0-13.json https://creativeprojects.</description></item></channel></rss>