<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on resticprofile</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on resticprofile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:58:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:24:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/linux/</guid><description>Installation via a script Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple script to download the binary automatically. It works on mac OS X, FreeBSD and Linux:
$ curl -sfL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creativeprojects/resticprofile/master/install.sh | sh It should copy resticprofile in a bin directory under your current directory.
If you need more control, you can save the shell script and run it manually:
$ curl -LO https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creativeprojects/resticprofile/master/install.sh $ chmod +x install.sh $ sudo ./install.sh -b /usr/local/bin It will install resticprofile in /usr/local/bin/</description></item><item><title>mac OS X</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/macosx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:22:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/macosx/</guid><description>Installation with Homebrew There&amp;rsquo;s a homebrew tap for resticprofile:
$ brew tap creativeprojects/tap $ brew install resticprofile You can also install restic at the same time with --with-restic flag:
$ brew install resticprofile --with-restic You can test that resticprofile is properly installed (make sure you have restic installed or the test will fail):
$ brew test resticprofile Upgrading resticprofile installed via homebrew is very easy:
$ brew update $ brew upgrade resticprofile Installation via a script Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple script to download the binary automatically.</description></item><item><title>Windows</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:24:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/windows/</guid><description>Installation using bash You can use a script if you&amp;rsquo;re using bash in Windows (via WSL, git bash, etc.)
$ curl -LO https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creativeprojects/resticprofile/master/install.sh $ ./install.sh It will create a bin directory under your current directory and place resticprofile.exe in it.
Manual installation (Windows) Download the package corresponding to your system and CPU from the release page Once downloaded you need to open the archive and copy the binary file resticprofile (or resticprofile.</description></item><item><title>Source</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/source/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:50:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/source/</guid><description>Installation from source You can download the source code and compile it, it&amp;rsquo;s actually very easy! all you need to have on your machine is:
git (with git-bash on Windows) go compiler GNU Make which is installed by default on many unix boxes. On debian based distributions (Ubuntu included) the package is called build-essential. To compile from sources:
$ git clone https://github.com/creativeprojects/resticprofile.git $ cd resticprofile $ make build Your compiled binary (resticprofile or resticprofile.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:57:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/upgrade/</guid><description>Once installed, you can easily upgrade resticprofile to the latest release using this command:
$ resticprofile self-update Please note on versions before 0.10.0, there was an issue with self-updating from linux with ARM processors (like a raspberry pi). This was fixed in version 0.10.0
resticprofile will check for a new version from GitHub releases and asks you if you want to update to the new version. If you add the flag -q or --quiet to the command line, it will update automatically without asking.</description></item><item><title>Docker</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:58:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/docker/</guid><description>Using resticprofile from a docker image You can run resticprofile inside a docker container. It is probably the easiest way to install resticprofile (and restic at the same time) and keep it updated.
But be aware that you will need to mount your backup source (and destination if it&amp;rsquo;s local) as a docker volume. Depending on your operating system, the backup might be slower. Volumes mounted on a mac OS host are well known for being quite slow.</description></item><item><title>Shell Completion</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/shell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:55:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/shell/</guid><description>Shell command line completions are provided for bash and zsh.
To load the command completions in shell, use:
# bash eval &amp;#34;$(resticprofile generate --bash-completion)&amp;#34; # zsh eval &amp;#34;$(resticprofile generate --zsh-completion)&amp;#34; To install them permanently:
$ resticprofile generate --bash-completion &amp;gt; /etc/bash_completion.d/resticprofile $ chmod +x /etc/bash_completion.d/resticprofile</description></item><item><title>Ansible</title><link>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/ansible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 23:47:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://creativeprojects.github.io/resticprofile/installation/ansible/</guid><description>Installation using Ansible Installation using Ansible is not streamlined, but here&amp;rsquo;s the playbook I&amp;rsquo;m using on my servers:
Playbooks resticprofile.yml (5 KB) This is very much work in progress. Once I get a stable ansible script I should publish it to Ansible Galaxy.
The playbook is installing (or upgrading):
latest restic binary to /usr/local/bin latest resticprofile binary to /usr/local/bin the resticprofile configuration file from a template file found in /resticprofile/{{ inventory_hostname }}/profiles.</description></item></channel></rss>